Clyde Shen

Aside of coding and creating software, I am also tutoring new programmers at a local organisation. I enjoy the process of software development as well as influencing others in this Industry. It makes me feel great.

Currently, I am part of an Agile (Scrum) team creating cloud based solution for kids industry in New Zealand. My main areas are .NET, C#, SQL and most importantly browser based technologies.

As a software developer, I really appreciate the following terms "enthusiastic, modest, trustworthy, honesty and hardworking", and I strive to keep myself align with them. Please give me a chance to tell you more stories about my experience and I might be the **problem solver** that you need.

EDUCATION

Auckland University of Technology (2011 - 2013)

Bachelor of Computing and Mathematical Science, Major in Computer Science

The top achiever in Bachelor of Computing and Mathematical Science at AUT

Oracle Certified Associate

Java SE 7 Programmer (OCAJP 7)

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

MICROSOFT

C#, MVC, ASP.Net, Team Foundation Server, Visual Studio

DATABASES

MySQL, SQL Server

OPERATING SYSTEM

Windows, Linux

TOOLS/LIBRARIES

NetBeans, Eclipse, Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, LaTeX, Jira, Confluence, Cordova, PhoneGap, LAMP, Webmin, Photoshop, TargetProcess

TECHNOLOGIES

JAVA, PHP, HTML5, JavaScript, CSS, JQuery, AJAX, Kendo UI, Bootstrap, Angular JS, Ionic, Codelgniter, Laravel, WordPress, Magento, JSON, Web API, Web Services, RESTful, Security, J2EE, Glassfish, Tomcat, Responsive UI, SEO

WORK EXPERIENCE

Central Station Software, Co. Software Developer

Sep 2015 – Current

28 Constellation Dr., Rosedale, Auckland

Development within a large scale software project using ASP.Net MVC, C#, Kendo UI, HTML5, JavaScript, CSS, Entity Framework and Microsoft SQL Server in Agile environment.

- Project: AIMY Plus is a cloud based software solution. It provides software as service for Child Programme Management & Real Time Booking & Financials. E.g. After School Care, Class, Children Academies, Sports Clubs and Tuition. It already accomplished more than 6 million dollar bookings within 6 months.
- Working as part of a developing team responsible for back-end and front-end developing of full features of the contact manager that is to manage more than 110,000 contact details in AIMY Plus.
- Optimizing legacy code and reducing redundant data to decrease response time from 8 seconds to 0.5 seconds in average.

Tang Ren, Ltd. Software Developer

May 2014 - Current

Level 3, 20 Augustus Terrace, Parnell, Auckland

Responsible for determining all necessary coding requirements for a sites creation including forms, e-commerce capability and specialized scripts and participating in the full life cycle of new website development.

- Implemented framework development and reduce development costs by at least 70%.
- Managed the web design and development of the entire client websites by using various CMS systems including WordPress or Magento, and page layout base on customized design, UI/UX, responsive web, general SEO.
- Frontend, backend development and maintenance of MVC architecture websites and an internal CMS development using PHP, Object-oriented programming, HTML5/CSS3, MySQL, WYSIWYG, AJAX, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap Framework, and LAMP toolsets.

Ann's Volcanic Motel Web Developer

April 2014 - May 2014

107 Malfroy Road, Rotorua, New Zealand

Responsible for maintaining features and capabilities of the website. Content and images update with FTP connection. Performing Functional Testing and modification for existing code.

- Increased traffic by 35% in one month, and page views per visit by 50%.
- Creating HTML pages based on graphic designs using PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and JQuery.

Assignment Marker Auckland University of Technology

July 2013 – December 2013

55 Wellesley Street East, Auckland Central

Responsible for collection and marking assignments for Algorithm Design and Analysis. Checking performance and cheating of assignments, and report to lecturer.

- Marker for Algorithm Design and Analysis
- Assignment collection and report

REFEREES

Mr. Ray Lu Technical Director

Central Station Software

Phone: +64 21-982288

Address: 28 Constellation Dr., Rosedale, Albany

Email: ray@codemeit.com

Dr. Jiamou Liu Senior Lecturer

School of Computer and mathematical Sciences, Auckland University of Technology

Phone: 09-9219999 ext. 5868

Address: 55 Wellesley Street East, Auckland Central

■ Email: jiamou.liu@aut.ac.nz

Miss Zishan Zhang

ANN'S VOLCANIC Motel

Phone: +64 21-2731392

Address: 107 Malfroy Road, RotoruaEmail: ann@rotoruamotel.co.nz

Marketing Director